# **TONMOY RUDRA**

(SOFTWARE ENGINEER)

Phone: (+88) 01921-619389

Email: tonmoyrudra1@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tonmoyrudra

**Experience: 3 Years+** 



#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Thinking "out of the box" to provide software-based solutions with AGILE Methodology. **3 years+** Experienced software engineer, committed to maintaining cutting edge technical skills and up-to-date industry knowledge. Strong in design and integration of problem-solving skills. Expert in **Front-end & Back-end with JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, NodeJS, Rx.Js, PHP, MySQL and No-SQL** with database analysis and design.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer**

## SurroundApps Inc.

Purana Paltan, Dhaka. (Jan 2017 - Present)

#### Responsibilities:

Here I am exploring myself as a Full-Stack Web Developer.

- Working with JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, Angular Material etc.
- HTML5, CSS3, SASS etc. for modern, responsive front-end web application development.
- Integrating web services using REST and JSON.
- Implement Rest API with Node. Js, Rx. Js, Express. Js, Apache Cassandra (no SQL).
- Improve Debugging log with test case.
- Integrate Payment Gateway (SSL Commerce & PayPal) on web application.
- Database Support and maintenance.

## **Trainee Software Engineer & Assistant Trainer**

#### **Nerd Castle Ltd**

Mirpur, Dhaka (Sep 2016 - Dec 2016)

#### **Responsibilities:**

Starting as a **Trainee Software Engineer** and **Assistant Trainer** of Web Application Development – Dot Net which is conduct by BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM)

### **PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS**

## 1. Alert Family & Alert Circle

**Description**: A Web/Android/IOS application that allows users to track their family members or other locations on a map, talk to them and also receive panic alert notifications when they are at risk. They can send out live alerts, SMS or start streaming live audio. (Project Link)

**Technology:** Front-end (Angular.JS & Material, Html, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript) and Backend (Rest API Implementation with Node.JS, Rx.JS)

#### 2. Video Chat Connect

**Description**: A one-stop shop for all video collaboration needs. It allows users to set up one to one or multi-party audio or video conferences and meetings hosted on this site. (Project Link)

**Technology:** Front-end (Angular.JS & Material, Html, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript) and Backend (Rest API Implementation with Node.JS, Rx.JS)

### 3. Cisco Instant Connect

**Description:** Cisco Instant Connect is a platform that enables push-to-talk (PTT) communications in a Cisco Unified Communications (UC) suite of products and other devices such as third-party radios and smartphones. It allows users to use their own devices that are the Apple IOS or Android operating systems, and user supported Cisco Unified IP Phone models to create an on-premises PTT solution. I am working with its Web team to develop admin panel and dashboard. (Project Link)

**Technology:** Front-end (Angular.JS & Material, Html, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript) and Backend (Rest API Implementation with Node.JS, Rx.JS)

## 4. Bangel Mobile QA Solution

**Description**: It's a Company informative Website. (Project Link)

Technology: Angular.JS, Html, CSS, JavaScript and fully responsive etc.

## 5. University Thesis-Project Automation System (UTPAS)

**Description:** Its fully Thesis-Project Automation System for university. The quest for quality in education emphasizes the role of planning and management. UTPAS is the primary system for operating universities thesis & project. (Academic Final Project)

**Technology:** C#, ASP.net, HTML, CSS, AJAX, jQuery, Bootstrap etc.

### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Strong understanding of web architecture concepts (HTTP request/response, session, cache, cookies etc)
- Experience in JavaScript and popular JS framework Angular.
- Experience with HTML5, CSS3, SASS/LESS, Bootstrap etc. for modern, responsive front-end web application development.
- Familiarity with web workflow automation tools such as npm.
- Experience integrating web services using REST and JSON.
- Familiarity with back-end application development with Node. Js, Rx. Js, Express. Js, Apache Cassandra.
- Programming Language: C, OOP (C++, C#)
- Framework & Web Component: JavaScript, Typescript, Angular, Angular Material, Node.JS, Rx.JS, ASP.net, MVC, jQuery, AJAX, HTML, CSS etc.
- Database & Server: My SQL, MS SQL, Apache Cassandra.

#### **OTHER SKILLS**

- Experience working on Agile teams
- Strong experience working with Git
- Good sense of best practices and code conventions

- XMPP messaging protocol, Push To Talk (PTT)
- Soft Skills: Communications, teamwork, sense of urgency, leadership & responsibility

## PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND AFFILIATIONS

- Skill for Employment Investment Program (SEIP) on Web App Development –.NET (dot NET) – Powered By BITM
- National Mobile Application Trainer and Innovative Application Development Program. –
   Powered by Ministry of ICT Division

#### **EDUCATION**

## B. Sc (Engr.) in Computer Science & Engineering (CSE)

International Islamic University Chittagong

Graduated, Dec, 2016. CGPA: 3.245 out of 4.00

## **M**EMBERSHIP

Bangladesh Computer Society

Membership Type: Associate Member

Membership No.: **AM-12495** Validation: 2018 - 2021

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name : **Tonmoy Rudra**Father's Name : Asish Kumar Rudra
Mother's Name : Pratima Rudra
Date of Birth : 30<sup>th</sup> Dec, 1994

Permanent Address : Vill: Kalipur, P.O: Izzat Nagar-4391, P.S: Banskhali

Dist.: Chattogram, Bangladesh

Present Address : 37/A, Box Culvert Road, Purana Paltan, Fayanaz Tower, 14th Floor

Room no: 14A, Dhaka, Dhaka GPO -1000

Known Languages : Bangla(native) & English.

#### REFERENCES

1. MD. ISMAIL

Head of Financial Solutions Development

**BRAC IT Services Limited** 

Cell: +88 01730704604

2. KAM Rashedul Mazid

MD of Raise IT Solutions Ltd. Co-Chairman of BASIS

Email: rahat@raiseit-bd.com